magic is a brilliant game that's been
going on for over 30 years and while
I've been playing it for at least half
of that Journey I'm still learning new
things about it every day
and to be honest with a 281 page raw
document that seems to grow every three
months or so I'm going to get it wrong
sometimes
so in this video I wanted to clarify two
small things that I got wrong in my
previous video as well as answer and
highlight a number of interesting
interactions that have Arisen from this
change that I discussed with the viewers
in the comments so let's jump into it
firstly changing the word card to
permanent isn't the reason why copies
and tokens can be double faced Wizards
have simply allowed tokens and copies to
be able to become double-faced cards
that's it
as John Jay puts it in the comments my
end result was correct but the way I got
there wasn't
thanks for clarifying John
secondly vizier of the many faces embalm
token cannot transform
after discussing the rule change with
some viewers in the comments I
eventually realized what I missed
and all it took was a discussion about
blade of shared souls and thing in the
ice
so crab asks if we create a token copy
of thing in the ice will it immediately
flip to awoken horror
the quick answer here is no as the token
will still come into play with four ice
counters on it
if you then remove the four ice counters
on it yes it will then flip to awoken
horror
Lucky Duck then asks
would this work with blade of shared
Souls with the token becoming a copy of
thing in the ice
and this is where it all made sense
so to answer lucky Duck's question and
work out this ruling we simply need to
ask is the 2-2 red Rebel creature a
single-faced or double-faced permanent
the short answer is it's a single-faced
permanent
on the flip side incubator tokens
explicitly say they transform into a
zero zero forexian artifact creature so
from that we know that incubator tokens
are double faced permanence
and one of the rules we clarified in the
previous video was
so will the token attach to Blade of
shared Souls transform after becoming a
copy off thing in the ice no it is a
single-faced permanent and cannot
transform
this answer then led me to realize my
mistake
vizier of the many faces in bomb token
is a token copy of vizier of the many
faces
and how many faces does vizier of the
many faces have
well it's just one it's a single face
card which means the token is also a
single face card which means
the token cannot transform
so with that out of the way here are
some quick fire interactions that were
brought up in the comments would this
rule change affect morph cards no the
rules for morph haven't changed if you
create a token copy of a morph your
token copy will become a 2-2 colorless
creature with no abilities
how does this rule change work with
dollhouse of Horrors
well you'll get a double faced token
copy of the transform card that you
exiled it will have all its written
abilities but both sides will have zero
power and toughness and in addition it
will have the ability this creature gets
plus one plus one for each construct you
control
the token also gains haste till end of
turn
what about token copies of transformer
cards the new rule applies here too
effectively convert is the exact same
thing as transform so yes you can
transform or convert your Decepticons
and Autobots tokens
alright that's all I've got for this
video
thanks again for all your support on my
channel recently I really appreciate it
I hope you'll all stick around and watch
my future videos
have a good night and I'll see you next
time